Also, let me say, I'm sorry. I know I'm
going to be a little bit of an [__]
here, but I'm kind of a little bit of an
[__] as a mentor. I'm like, "Oh,
okay. So, this is your dream. Gotcha.
Gotcha. Why aren't you doing that?" You
know, you know, like that's just a
little bit of of who I am as a mentor.
[Music]
Yeah,
dude. Sup, hackers. So, Zero Trust World
just happened and Threat Locker dropped
some pretty cool stuff. My favorite of
the bunch was Threat Locker Cloud
Control and I'll tell you why. Okay, so
when you're trying to hack an
organization nowadays, what's kind of
like the go-to approach? Well, for most
it's going to be set up evil engineext
and send out a bunch of fishing emails,
right? That way you don't have to worry
about um two-factor authentication or
anything like that because evil
engineext is just going to let them put
in their password, their 2FA, and then
just hand you back a session token to
interact with uh Microsoft 365. So,
Threat Locker realized this was a
problem. And so, what they decided to do
was build cloud control, which uses the
threat locker agent to sync into
Microsoft cloud conditional access a
list of approved IP addresses from which
a user can connect. Right? So then an
attacker gets that token that they stole
by Evil Engine X. They try to use it to
interact with Microsoft 365 and boom,
they're burned because they're not
coming from a permitted network and they
lose access. It's pretty sick. It's a
great solution to the problem. So
definitely check it out. Threat Locker
Cloud Control. All right, back to the
show. All righty, my man. Here we go. We
got the studio set up. This is the first
time we've done a podcast in the new uh
studio live, so I'm excited. Um, for
everyone who doesn't know, this is
Sosaki Gucci. He's one of my best
friends from when I lived in Japan and
uh has become a hacker, a full-time bug
bounty hunter over the past couple
years. Um, and that's been a really fun
story. So, uh, he's actually in town,
uh, doing some hacking with me,
visiting, that sort of thing. And I
figured we would do a little podcast to
sort of talk about, um, your experience
as a becoming a full-time book bounty
hunter uh, from zero before and Yeah.
and and I think it was episode 40, if
the notes are correct, uh back in in
2023,
um that you joined the podcast, came on
the podcast with Kodi and uh we started
talking about, you know, Bug Bounty
mentorship. So, we'll do a little bit of
that today. Um we're going to do a live
mentorship session and just kind of do a
check-in. Um and then we'll kind of hit
some of the other stuff that as you've
grown as a hacker has become more
relevant to this podcast. So, dude, I'm
so excited to have you on here like as
an as a guest and I mean as a guest as a
as a guest. Like I we were sort of
debating before before the podcast
started like you know yes we could take
an angle for this podcast where we could
talk about you mostly as a as a mentee
and do like a mentee checkin and we will
do that. But also I'm looking at this
stuff here and this is good [__] dude.
This is like this is stuff that I would
invite you on the podcast to talk about.
So, um, this is the first time that I'm
going to have you do this, but, uh, you
know, when we have somebody on the
podcast, they have to prove their worth
first. Okay. Uh, and they have to
present a bug. Present a bug. Yeah.
Okay. So, but and and I'll I'll tell you
I'll tell you this, you know, obviously
doing this in English is a gift to me.
So, thank you. So, and uh because of
that and also because I have a life
dream of doing a podcast in Japanese um
we are going to switch at the end of
this episode uh into Japanese and I will
also present a bug so that I will
understand the difficulty of what you're
about to go through. Um that's kind of
more scary to me too because you I kind
of have to lead the you know for you.
So, but you also do what Bug Bounty JP
podcast is that what it is? But that's
where like there's another guy leading
the conversation. Yeah, I just talked so
it was the
different. All right, let's uh let's
let's jump in. Which bug you want to
start with? You got a Google and a
Facebook bug, which I think is great.
So, which which one you want to which
one you want to start with? Uh I think
uh probably uh maybe with Facebook bug
because I think it's okay. A lot
simpler. Yeah, let's do it. So the
Facebook bug is um it's like I'm a
little scared with like presenting this
bug because you know I've seen many
people present their bugs here and this
this is like this is cool because I
found it on Facebook but it's not too
complicated. But anyways so I found this
is a stored DOM XSS that I found on one
of their open source project XL.
So the the reason I I started to look
into this is so for one uh I think it
was Space Raccoon. Yeah. We found some
pretty sick like clipboard. Yeah. Was it
like uh Yeah. paste like a clipboard.
Yeah. Yeah. XSS. And he found like
pretty cool XSS like probably three four
years ago and made a blog post about it.
So I knew the product and then like last
year I read somebody's blog post. I
forgot whose blog post but it was also
about XSS on X roll
and that so clearly they have a problem
with XS. Yeah. And that one compared to
space reference blog was it was a great
read but at the same time wasn't
technically as complex as space
reference one. And I was like actually
kind of impressed or surprised that you
know Facebook has this level of problem.
It's like you know like it gave you a
little bit of hope right. Yeah. Yeah.
And then and plus uh I forgot the
context but I met like a manager of meta
banani program back in like last
December cuz he came to Japan for for
his work and and he was like Facebook is
not as hard as you think and I'm like
well I don't know about that but you
know that right when I saw the schedule
blog and I kind of wanted to do bit of a
um source code review. So I was like
maybe I'll give it a try and the bug
was so
stores for one
and so I started to look into just all
the like syncs where they do like string
concatenation. It doesn't happen a lot
of times but I just found one thing
where they they do bit of strong
concatenation when they like convert SVG
to X casual. Then X casual is a to give
it a bit of context it's um uh like
whiteboard app. Yeah. It's like you can
you can it's a web app where you can
like draw different shapes and like
create graphics essentially. Right. And
then within that app uh you've got many
different like shapes graphics that you
can use and and you can import them and
they have like x casual extension too.
And the the strong concatenation I found
was where they convert SVG into X casual
extension. M and first I wasn't sure
like where they like using it but I was
like so let's check out like where
they're using it and I found that
um it seems like they allow user to
um how to explain like they allow user
to export like import their own
um drawing or the drawing object by
specifying
uh like host or like I forgot
parameters name like like something like
host query parameter. So if you do like
import question mark host equal your
domain.com and if you host the XAR
object there with SVG and they import it
and
then make it into XAR object. Ah okay.
Okay. So you there's a slashimp import
endpoint. You can provide a host for it.
But I'm not sure if it was a slash
import but like somewhere something like
that and then it will it will reach out
to your host grab is it just any file
type or is it specifically for SVGs? I
think it was uh I should have reviewed
that like I think there's like a few
types and then like depending on like
the content and also like content type
like they'll like triage it and they
they'll they'll sort it into and a
different Excal object flow and and so
going back just real quick I wanted to
go back to what you were saying before
with regards to string concatenation. So
you said you were looking for string
concatenation. Were you looking for like
specifically
HTML like strings and then concatenating
it with a variable or what was your
approach to find that sync in the first
place? Uh I think uh so
um so so it's kind of complicated but um
so basically for the so they they
essentially a whiteboard object
whiteboard app and on whiteboard
everything is canvas canvas like HTML
canvas canvas. Yeah, there's no SVG like
there's no pos possibility for excss but
for like they have this library feature
where they can you can store your own or
like you know imported objects and then
put it into your canvas into your
whiteboard and in whiteboard nothing
happens but within library or like
within preview which is a different
future but you know right some future
uses like SVG and such like temporarily
to display like those options and such.
So I was like I need to find place where
like this you know this
happens and
that that was my approach that and that
was the approach. Okay. So then you find
the place where the string concatenation
occurs. You figure out a way to load
your uh malicious file into the the
person's account. So if you just hit
make them hit that import you know csurf
essentially it'll grab the object from
your host and then just kind of plop it
into their whiteboard. no prop into
their library their library. So it
doesn't trigger right off the bat, but
once they open library like every time
they open library that like object is
like made into like XAure object with
HTML without canvas tag because it's not
whiteboard right app then it's not
whiteboard it's not library and then
they trigger XSS. Okay. Okay. Okay. So,
so you know when it's in the whiteboard,
it's in a canvas, so no XSS, but when
they go to the library, there's like a a
preview or something like that of that
and that uses a different format like a
SVG or something like that to display it
and that's where you get the XSS. Nice,
dude. Very solid. All right. Like maybe
I I I don't actually remember like too
much of the details, so maybe something
was wrong about it, but I think that's
pretty much it. That sounds about right.
Now, now was it, you know, at the end of
the day, were you able to specify
arbitrary HTML tags? Were you just
injecting like an onload handler or into
the SVG tag or what? Just like image
like on error sort of thing. That that
works. Clean payload. Yeah, I didn't
check like any restriction there, but
that worked. Wow, dude. Very nice. All
right. Well, see, you know, but think
about it, man. you were saying like you
read Space Raccoon's blog and you read
this other person's blog about Excal and
you're like, "Oh, you know, this doesn't
seem so bad, right?" And then you had
the confidence to go find it and you get
a bounty and you find a cool, you know,
vulnerability, right? You're doing the
same thing for all the guests now. You
know, they say, "Oh, yeah, there was an
import parameter and then it just, you
know, populates this SVG, you know, on
the library page." That's uh that
doesn't seem so bad, you know. But then,
yeah. So, yeah. So if you say that like
I have to do the same thing as all the
other guests is like I I said it like as
if as if as if it was easy but it was
like before finding this sink. Yeah. I
think it took me like four days finding
nothing like oh this turns out to be not
vulnerable and then like on fourth day
fifth day I was like oh what is this
thing? Yeah, we just had this earlier or
like what yesterday, right? You spent
like four hours. I'm sorry to call you
out, but we were hacking together
yesterday and there was like, you know,
there was a post message uh that we saw
come through on one of these targets and
you we we love to see a post message
that contains a raw HTML string. Like,
doesn't that just like get the blood
flowing a little bit? Like, exactly. We
saw it. Yeah. And and so so like we get
excited. We're like, oh, this is going
to be excess. you know, they got a
campaign going on. This is going to be
easy money. And um and so so like goes
through this whole process to like build
an HTML page and like do this handshake
with a post message. And then we get to
the end of it and it's like what is it
like react and they use React to build
like we build HTML based off of my like
HTML and there's nothing we can do about
that, you know, like it's just I I won't
give up. Yeah. Oh my god. So, well, we
recently also, you know, we'll talk
about this as well, um, but we also had
a couple syncs sort of like this in a
Google bug recently, um, where we had a
post message to HTML injection um, on
the page. But when you just get when you
get stuck in these like react sanitize
or Angular sanitize functions, it's like
if you can bypass Angular or React
Sanitize, then that's the bigger
problem, you know, like you don't need
to worry about reporting your little
post message bug. you need to report
Angular sanitized bypass, right? Um, but
it was interesting because, you know,
just like you said, you're not giving
up. Um, that episode that we did with
Kevin Mizu and Kevin Mizu's um, write up
recently on like how to bypass DOM
purify or via misconfigurations and
stuff like that was really eye opening
for me on how to attack HTML sanitizers.
Um, and just try to take advantage of
the fact that if there is any
modification that is done to the string
post sanitization
that you're you're messing with with it,
right? You know, you're messing with the
integrity of that of that sanitize. Um,
so that's one of the things I always go
to look for. So I won't blame you
because I also went down the rabbit hole
of auditing Angular sanitize on this
Google bug. Um, but yeah, it seems
pretty hopeless whenever you're in those
sort of Angular React sanitiz
situations. You have to say so.
Yeah. Yeah. All right. So, that was one.
You got a pass. But actually, actually,
number two. Number two, we're gonna
we're actually going to do two bugs
today. This bug was actually a
collaboration between So and I on a
Google target. And um we we may have to
cut this segment right now. We'll see.
Uh you know, if if we do, I'm sorry.
Hopefully, we'll get the chance to talk
about it sometime, but um I guess we'll
cut now if we do not get permission to
disclose this. Um all right, so you're
still listening to this. We do have
permission to disclose it, which rocks.
So um so let's go ahead and and jump
into it. Um do you want to tag team this
one or you want to take a shot at it or
what?
Uh I think I I'll try to explain first
and then you jump in if I if my my
explanation is not clear. All right, hit
us. Yeah. Yeah. So the thing we found
was um um wait I'm not sure how how much
we how much detail we can go into but uh
so don't say don't say where we find
found it you can say Google and then
technical details but don't say what
product we found it in. Yeah. So, the
first Justin found some like interesting
feature in Google like that's like
pretty much that's used pretty much
everywhere in Google products like
regardless of like google.com,
YouTube.com like you know different
domains
and so that this is so hard to do like
all right do you why don't you let me
queue it up and then you talk about the
technical details okay because it is a
little bit difficult when you're trying
not to disclose some information. So
this is a Google um this is a component
used by a bunch of Google products uh
like you said on YouTube on Google on
you know any of their domains and um it
for the business use case which we can't
say it is essential that it be able to
be used on all these different um
domains and um it creates an iframe and
it does some stuff with that iframe uh
and what we are trying to to take
advantage of here is that this product
has to be so versatile So um universally
accessible um because it makes doing
origin checks really difficult um and
allows us to sort of insert ourselves as
uh as a parent or as a um you know as a
window in the same um tab group as the
specific frame which allowed us to get
access to the post message handlers
which allowed us to send some post
messages. So um then we've sort of teed
it up there. Now you can try kind of try
to take it and and explain some of the
technical details. Yeah. So so basically
like like Justin said it's like an
iframe. Yeah. Where it receives um like
some information like some information
from Google related domains a Google
related services. I'd say it's like a
configuration post messenger. Yeah. And
then based off of those information
received the iframe sends a like like a
few requests to Google API to do you
know to send stuff and such and that's
that's like the kind of overview how I
see it
and so we we found this post message on
the France Rosen post message tracker.
Shout out to France. And a shout out to
France Rosen. And and that post message
uh that post message content included
like bunch of
different stuff that looks like a
component of HTTP request. Yeah. And I
think what was interesting about this is
it and you did a really good job of it
as we were building it out because uh it
was protobuff format, right? It didn't
have like keys and values. It was just
like an array with values and um and
then Oh, yeah. Yeah. you know, and I I
kind of let you be and work on this for
a little bit while I was working on this
other bug. And then I came back and man,
I just loved to see it. You had, you
know, you had a a JavaScript snippet
sort of built out and, you know, where
it would send the post message and then
next each field you broke it out into a
different line and then you had like a
comment next to it and says, "Okay, this
one does this. This one is like that
that." and you just sort of identified
the flow of each one of those arguments
which ended up being essential to
actually exploiting the vulnerability.
Yeah.
So anyways,
yeah. So like Justin said, I kind of
tried to f like understand how each
component works, how how each component
is being used. And yeah, like you said,
it wasn't uh initially clear that it's
uh something to build HTTP requests, but
as I go through JavaScript, I just
realize, oh, this is, you know, this is
HTTP path or this is, you know, body and
this is a query parameter. So what what
we found out is with a lot lot of
restrictions we could potentially send
post message from our site to that
iframe in a way that that I frame sends
like partially controlled HTTP request
to Google API and uh one good thing
about like one good thing about for us
is that
um some of the things are built uh some
of the things that we don't have control
on include authorization header. So for
that like partially control request
includes victim's authorization header
and the other thing that was interesting
was uh if the the request is successful
the response is sent back by the post
message. You love to see it. You
freaking love to see it man. So what we
can do is like kind of sea surf thing
but at the same time we can see the
response back too. love it with with
victims and header sent. So
So that was our attack vector is like we
try to find to hit an endpoint that
uh that responds with like users
information or something like that and
we read that that that was our attack
vector and then
yeah that's overview and then we then we
sort of hit into a roadblock with this
uh domain validation thing. Yeah. Yeah.
So we that was the first block which is
a domain violation. So the the first
time I saw this post message listener
there's no origin check. So I was like
okay so you know I don't even have to
think about that. So I'll just uh think
about the the request content and then
once I figure out the request content I
realized that they're actually sending
two requests instead of one request. And
uh the first request is like slash
domain uh question mark domain equal
your domain like original post message
and then second domain is like the one
we can read the response. Yeah. And now
apparently they were you using that
first request as a domain check. Right.
So, so essentially they had instead of
doing like the domain check at at the
post message level, they were taking our
origin sticking a in a domain parameter
and then hitting an API to tell them
whether or not we should be allowed to
access this or be able to send this post
message, right? Which kind of makes
sense too because like like we
mentioned, this like component was used
everywhere, not just on google.com. So,
you know, you want to keep it like a
versatile. Yeah. Like easy to configure.
So they they might wanted to configure
this way instead of you know checking
the origin. Sure. And so we keep that uh
that block but uh one one thing I
realized that is
uh for the first request no not second
request the first request for domain
check we have just a bit of control on
that first request too which is great
parameter. So we could uh specify
parameter. Mhm.
So like you know obviously the first
thing I was thinking was like oh maybe
if I specify domain equal google.com
they might override like domain equal my
my domain.com and then they might give
me you know they might pass a check
right. So it would become like a request
to slche domain. Oh yeah. And then it
would say question mark domain equals
googleg google.com. That's the one we
specified. And they hash and and then oh
you were going to try to truncate the
Yeah. So put like a hashtag so he
truncates off the and domain equals
attackersite.com. Yeah. So I didn't
explain this well but like yes. So in
that post message we could have just
specified the uh httm http request query
parameter uh key value pair. Yeah sure.
And those things come before the like
domain equal my domain.com. So as like
if we can put hash in it, we could
override it truncate the path. Yeah. Or
the query parameters. Yeah. Yeah. and
then still we can send this request and
we might potentially be able to you know
excfuture something but that turned out
to be uh that didn't work right and the
reason for that is uh so we read
JavaScript and they're doing more
thorough approach of just taking out all
the key value parameter and create an
array like arch
and then at the end of the array they
have their you know check thing domain
equal my domain.com and And so so they
they put all of them like one by one and
during that process because domain equal
my my domain.com is at the last that
always overrides like even if I attempt
like domain or google.com before you you
know what I'm saying? Yeah. So they set
them in a map, right? So domain and then
and then you know the value they parse
all of our parameters and then at the
end they say they add override whatever
is is there with domain equals whatever.
Yeah. So yeah, so we could send like
something invalid equal something
invalid and domain equal Google domain
equal my domain.com. Yeah. But we
couldn't override that domain. Right.
Okay. So we're still stuck there. So how
did you get around it? So
uh so that was a I it wasn't like you
know like strategical like thoughtful
approach. I just, you know, you know
what? I'm just gonna, you know, dump all
the like characters using like word
computer and put that thing right before
D of domain and right after N of domain.
Yeah. And see if those will pass because
we tried also like capitalization and
stuff like that, right? But the
capitalization wouldn't let us to
wouldn't let us get back by it. It was
like lowercasing everything or something
like that. Yeah. And uh I was kind of at
that point I was like that was like a
hopeless like attempt. Yeah. I know it
not that's not going to work but I'm
just going to do it. And then and then
when I see that when I saw the like
intruder history I saw some some of them
s being successful like including one
like domain equal
uh like google.com
in which case they send like domain
equal google.com and domain equal my
domain.com right and I don't know what
the heck happens on that end but like if
I send that like three times or four
times and then like one of them succeeds
dude for like whatever reason. Dude, I
remember when you found that and then we
I think it was actually like literally
right here in this exact spot. So is
like sitting over there. He says,
"Justin, I got it." I was upstairs. I
run down here. You show me it. And then
we just start jumping up and down and
screaming and like, "No way that that
works." It's crazy to me, man, that it
worked like what was it like 30% of the
time? Like there was some weird load
balancer in there where it was like okay
I'm one of these like four servers or
whatever is gonna take strip the the dot
character from the beginning of the
maybe so yeah super weird. Yeah I have
no idea what happens back end but
worked. Yeah. Yeah. The problem is, you
know, we we don't know yet what we can
do with, you know, us being able to send
partially control parameter to specific
Google private API, right? Because we
haven't figured that for out, you know.
So, it's not it's not like a super win
yet, but that was still pretty exciting.
Yeah. So, it took us like three days to
come to like domain check thing. Yeah.
Yeah, but because because of three days
work, we were so excited and like we got
to push push through the all the all the
you know blocks to come in the future.
So that's a that was the first block and
what was it? So the so from there then
we we established that we were able to
communicate with this post message
handler and trigger these these requests
to the API that we wanted to do and get
the responses back. Right. Yeah. If the
request is successful, right? So yeah
then at that point so because of some
restriction we couldn't bypass uh there
are only like a few API Google API we
could hit and we kind of enumerate all
the all the ready query using like
Google discovery document and so we
pretty much found nothing
uh
except one API getbased request
returning email and sad thing is our
request is postbased and we couldn't
change post to get that that was
something we couldn't control right and
then
yeah and and and then from there I think
you since it was it was post we had to
figure out a way to hit these different
API endpoints though right first before
we before we did that and if I recall
correctly that happened via a client
side path reversal oh yeah yeah
So, so that's a that's another block I
completely skipped here is a yeah there
is a so like like mentioned like some of
the things could be configurable some of
the things in HTTP are configurable
including HTTP path so like part of HTTP
path yeah just one segment yeah one like
ID is something we had control on and
they're using XHR on the client side and
they don't have any validation before
So we could inject like dot do slash to
uh traverse back to the root. So which
allowed us to send pretty much
whatever to whatever endpoints. We don't
have control on cost but we had control
on like any
uh like the path being sent. So so
that's why we could keep arbitrary uh
endpoint of right of given. Yeah. And
and but then we're still stuck with the
post request. We looked at the
discoveries documents, couldn't find
anything we could do with the post
request, right? Yeah. Yeah. So So then
what happened? Then like there like uh
we started to do some like hopeless
attempts again. Like I I think I spent
like four hours on that. And one thing I
found which turned out to be absolutely
useless is like I found like this X
method override header. Yeah, if I send
it like Google will accept like if I
send post request with X method override
header being get they'll say as get. So
I was like oh if I can specify this
header then like that we victorious the
thing is we can't add any parameter like
header. Yeah, that wasn't something we
have control and such. So that that took
us like what like probably pretty much a
day. Yeah, a day on that I think. Yeah.
And then there I almost completely gave
up there and then Justin moved on to um
completely different target of but like
Google, right? Yeah. But I was still
looking at Google. Yeah. Yeah. And then
I think I I still remember was like 11
o'clock like in the morning like like
suddenly you were like a I got this cell
and then you know he what he found is
like
um was RPC. Yeah. So, so essentially
what what it turned out to be was that
all almost all of Google's APIs are
accessible via multiple uh ways. You can
you can hit, you know, the path directly
like a like a normal REST API, you know,
SL API whatever um and then hit those
endpoints with get post whatever or you
can use the RPC interface. Yeah. Um and
and the RPC interface has some quirks to
it, but one of the things that works
really well for us is that it's all
postbased, right? Yeah. But the other
thing that doesn't work for us is they
use a little bit different protobuff
content type. Yeah. So we actually tried
that right we actually we've already
like tried hitting RPC endpoints didn't
work because content type is different.
That's like you know three days before
you scream right right here. Right.
Yeah. So what was the final discovery
then? So that was your discovery. So
okay, final discovery was this guys was
that um on some Google APIs that utilize
RPC, there is a a header that you or a a
queer parameter that you can provide
called dollar sign HTTP headers with a
capital H for headers. Um and what that
allows you to do is just specify
arbitrary HTTP headers. Um which was
exactly what we needed. So, you know,
putting that whole chain together, what
we ended up doing was changing the
content type then to the correct
protobuff content type, hitting an RPC
endpoint with a post request, which is
exactly how it's supposed to be and the
past reversal and the path reversal,
right? And to hit the RPC endpoints, and
then we specified uh we also had full
control of the body of the request from
the the the post from the post message.
Yeah. So then putting it all together,
bypass the domain check, hit the client
side path traversal, traverse to the RPC
call, uh specify the HTTP headers to
convert the content type to uh
protobuff, and then send protobuff in
the body to send a valid protobuff
request to the API, which then gets
piped back out via post message to our
our our handler. Yeah. And then that
hand obviously was like sends the
response back to our side. Yep. By a
post message. So we users like you know
Yeah. some information. Yeah. We were
able to then use that to do a bunch of
things. One, you know, we could leak
some PI about the user. We could also
modify like make the user send a
specific type of um object to the API
that would change their account. And we
could also extract a bunch of data, not
only about the user, but about these uh
objects that they have in this API. Um,
so that was a really fun bug, dude. Give
me some, man. That was that was a blast.
Um, very fun collab. Okay, so we're we
we took some time on that one. Um, but
let's go ahead and uh move to some of
these other sections that we have um in
the in the doc for today. Um, you want
to do the live mentorship session now or
do you want to talk about reflector
first? live mentorship. Let's do that
one first. Okay. All right. So, let's
So, so let me kind of set the stage for
this a little bit. Like, like I've said
before, I do some occasional bugani
mentorship, but it's pretty much only
for people that I know in real life um
and or are, you know, providing a
service to the podcast or, you know,
something like that. There's some other
exchange of services. Um shout out to to
uh Andrew Ninjer who did my tattoo for
me in exchange for some mentorship. Um,
and when we do these mentorship
sessions, a lot of the time what I'm
spending time doing is figuring out, you
know, what my mentees want to do with
their Bug Bounty career and helping them
get there. And it doesn't necessarily
have to be, you know, bug bounty is is
the full goal, as we'll talk about later
today. It could also be bug bounty as a
stepping stone to get somewhere else in
your career. Um, so I don't know. So, we
haven't sort of compared notes on this
in a little while and even though you're
here in person, like things have been
really busy lately, so we haven't had
the chance to sit down much. So, I'm
glad we're getting the chance to do that
now on pod.
Um, you I guess five years ago, you were
a French
major at at school and you know, we met
and uh you know, you got interested in
hacking and you since totally changed
your career path and are now a full-time
buck bounty hunter. Um but before you
were in, you know, consulting for a
little bit as a pentester um with some
companies in Japan. So that's kind of uh
your history. Uh you've been doing
full-time Bug Bunny for how long now?
For probably uh eight months. Eight
months. Okay. And you you made that
transition from a pretty uh
wellrespected uh Japanese consultancy,
you know, uh in Japan. Um, how are you
feeling about that transition? Where do
you want to be? You know, what are your
goals for Bug Bounty and your security
career?
Um, I think so for for the first
question of like how was the transition?
Uh, I think uh
well for for one it was a good
transition.
Um, the thing I like, so there are
things I I like better about Pakaban and
like better about, you know, working as
full-time content. One thing I really
like about being a full-time Bakani
hunter is like you can always focus on
like interesting stuff. Like sometimes
as panester, you need to, you know,
write those reports or deal with those
uh specific targets that are super super
soft. Yeah. Yeah. And also sometimes
something is not you see like you're
pretty sure that nothing's there like
not because you haven't checked but
because literally nothing there but you
sometimes have to do some like you know
standardized like you know Yeah. Just
check the boxes. Yeah.
So that's something I don't have to do
anymore. The other thing I like better
about Pagbani is that when you're not
performing well, you don't get paid. And
as a
pentester, you like that about Pakan? I
mean, I I hate that, but I al also I
like that at the same time. Yeah, I hate
that because as a pentester sometimes I
find I don't find good things, but I
still get, you know, monthly salary,
right? And I feel like uh you know, why
why am I getting paid in the first
place, right, without find anything?
that that's I feel like that's so
informed by a bug bounty first
experience right because if you think
about anywhere else in in the world like
you know any other job uh very often you
are paid for your effort you know and
the business owner absorbs the risk
right they they bet on you they say okay
so I think you're a good pentester so
I'm going to guarantee you some money
and I'm going to take on the risk that
you're not doing a good job right
personally and I'm going to harvest the
upside if you do do a good job, right?
I'm gonna I'm gonna get the margin for
that, right? Um, but in Buck Bounty,
it's it's results for, you know, money
for results. Yeah. So, yeah, but that
does fit to your personality a little
bit better. I think you like to earn
stuff. Yes. Yeah. But that's also
something I So, that was something I
hate about in job.
But you know it's of course it's tough
to you know not to get any money if you
don't find anything style and especially
because of uh like the findings are
technical like the or the things I find
is so I mostly focus on client side bug
like doxs and all like all weird stuff.
So I usually shoot for I usually look
for like one click based account
takeover. Mhm. Highest impact you can
get on the client side. Yeah, that's the
main thing. And I always try to focus on
programs that pay monthly as high at
least because some some program pay
excess is medium. So I I I skip those.
Yeah. Because I don't want to like argue
too much. And the the problem is like so
last year I found like 60 bucks
like the the you know what I wanted to
say 60 bucks is great dude. Yeah, but 60
bucks is, you know, if you split it up,
it's like one bug per six days. Yeah.
Sometimes you find like one bug per like
two days, but sometimes you find one bug
for two weeks. Yeah. And if you like see
annually, it's fine because most of them
are high. So I can, you know, make my
living and especially in Japan, things
are cheap, which seems to be surprising
to some people, but yeah. So that's
fine. But, you know, on a daily basis,
sometimes it's kind of stressful, right?
Because sometimes you don't get paid for
like two weeks and think, "Oh, last two
weeks I made zero money." It's
stressful, dude. It is stressful. Yeah.
So, how are you dealing with that
stress? And do you feel like that is
good like well fit to your lifestyle
long term or Yeah, that's probably the
biggest issue I have right now as a
full-time and if I ever want to uh go
back to any sort of full-time job, which
I still
consider maybe doing
That'd be the reason. So, so I guess let
me ask you this. Like one of the big
things that I talk about with my mentees
and I I I appreciate about my own
full-time book bounty experience is that
um I I have unlimited freedom. Like if I
and I utilize that. I mean, you've seen
that I I'm I'm in and out of this office
often during the day, you know, and I'm
going to, you know, run some errand or,
you know, deal with something, you know,
outside or whatever. like the I I
utilize that freedom a lot and I feel
like that is really valuable for a lot
of people but I don't know that that is
quite as valuable for you because you do
enjoy the journey of hacking so much
more than almost anything else in life
right like so do do you think you value
that freedom I mean obviously use the
freedom to look at things that you're
interested in but you don't necessarily
value that time freedom right probably
know as much as you do yeah yeah so I
Guess that that's one component of like
should you be a full-time hunter or
versus should you go back to, you know,
a a career at a at a job. Yeah. Um I
guess another another fact of that
factor of that would be the technical
intrigue, right? Like you said, you
know, being interested in in the things
that you're hacking. You can always do
that as a bug bounty hunter, but you
can't always do that at a job unless
you're in like a researcher role, right?
Would have you thought about like doing
a researcher-l like role or anything
like that? No, I just feel like, you
know, I need to get better at it. Get
better at hacking more before becoming
researcher is like what I feel right
now. Yeah. I think, you know, our
conversations we've had in the the past,
growth was a big thing for you, right?
So, I mean, do you still how do you
think your growth trajectory is as a
full-time book bounty hunter versus like
being in an environment where perhaps
you could be around other hackers that
are more senior, more advanced? At least
from my experience, I think being a
bunny hunter is um let me grow faster
for sure because you know I always have
this stress of of stress or you know
pressure of I need to make to get
results. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So I mean it
seems like a pretty growth heavy
environment, right? Why are you thinking
about going back to a company? But uh
this is something that relates to what I
said previously which is I find access
and all thing a lot is that you know if
I value make if I value the like part of
bunny aspect of bbani or making money
then I have to focus on those things
that I know I can find parts on like do
xss false message those things like I'm
not super confident finding it anywhere
But I end up I typically end up finding
those things. And what happens is
because I need to earn money.
I focus on those and I can't really
spend like as much time I want on other
fields that I'm not I'm good at. Okay.
So let's fact check that real quick.
Okay. So, so I hear you saying that you
feel like you need to earn money because
of the stress, but you are also saying
so, so let me ask this. How does your
earnings compared to your cost of
living?
It's pretty good. Right. How does your
earnings compare to a salary as a
consultant in Japan? It's uh better.
Yeah. Right. Is it like I guess well I
you don't have to answer this if you
don't want to but can you give a a
factor to it you know can you say like
it is 1.2x 2x, one, you know, 5x, you
know, where does it sit at? I think it
obviously depends on like each and every
year, but I think last year was like 2x,
like 2x, right? So So you've got margin
in your in your bug bounty earnings,
right? You can you can say um I don't
have to earn money right now, right? I
can I can go study these vol types that
may not produce results, right?
uh and and you know still pay
myself you know 5,000 or whatever out of
my my you know account my business bank
account each month. Um are you doing
that that right now or are you just kind
of having all of the money pass through
into your you're just doing that? Yeah.
Having no dude it's it's it's I you know
I I don't practice what I preach to be
perfectly honest. Like to be honest I do
the same thing but I also don't have a
lot of money earning stress. like I am
confident enough at this point where I'm
like ah it's going to be fine, you know,
like so I just kind of let I kind of let
it pass pass through, right? But what I
always say to the mentees in the
beginning is like you should especially
if you're worried about it, you should
build up a amount of money in your
business bank account and then pay
yourself a salary each month that is
equivalent to, you know, your cost of
living plus however much you want to
save or whatever, right? set set some
low, you know, not super ambitious
amount to pull out, you know, each time
and then you can take a month and go
study other bone types. Yeah. Are you
So, you're not doing that. Why aren't
you doing that?
I think uh also, let me say, I'm sorry.
I know I'm going to be a little bit of
an [__] here, but I'm kind of a
little bit of an [__] as a mentor.
I'm like, "Oh, okay. So, this is your
dream. Gotcha. Gotcha. Why aren't you
doing that?" You know, you know, like
that's just a little bit of of who I am
as a mentor. Um I don't know what do you
think about that? I think for financial
aspect uh if I if I look my earning on
an annual basis it's actually there's
actually no concern that I think I have
right now right so that is why I don't
build up that system but on the other
hand like I'd say I'm trying to
uh reduce that like meaningless concern.
Yeah, rather by getting better
technically like getting better at
hacking and if I can you know find more
bugs if I can earn more money if I know
I can earn you know like you said I
don't necessarily have to earn more
money but if I have more confident like
you have and say like oh if I if I you
know locked in if I log in for like week
I can find bugs I can get money and then
if I have that confidence I think I
could probably, you know, kind of fix up
a little bit. Okay, is what I'm
thinking, right? And that's, you know,
and the way to get to that that
confidence is what do you think that
that is a skill issue or do you think
that that is a like
and and let let me let me rephrase that.
How do you get to I'm going to take the
premise that that is the solution, which
I don't think is is the solution, right?
But let's just say that that is the
solution. The steps you should be taking
for that is is going to be to try to
grow as a hacker, right? And you do that
by trying new vulnerability types and
researching new vulnerability types. But
in order to do that, you can't be
earning money or at the same pace as you
would if you're just searching for DOMXS
and ATL, right? Are you able to do that
trade-off? Do you think do you think the
the concern of of not earning money will
override your ambitions to grow as a
hacker? I think I maybe not fully maybe
not as much as I want to do but I'm
doing it partially like as of right now
and I I mean I told you this before too
but you know the reason I came visit
your place like what probably the
biggest reason like in terms of hacking
is to get better at fields I'm not get
I'm not good at so if I just wanted to
focus on earning money I probably uh
should have stayed in Japan, you know,
in my house just, you know, in your in
your dark room hacking. Yeah, hacking
all days. But I was like, you know, for
now, if I calm down, see my previous
year's journ like on annual basis, not
take like last five days, right? I'm
doing fine. Yeah. And if I go visit
Justin, then I definitely learn things
I'm not good at. Okay. Yeah. So, so, so
you're taking a step towards growth by
coming here and trying to absorb some of
that. Yeah. And I did I did I did learn
some I'll say many things already here.
So, yeah. But yet yet that that's so but
we also were focusing on post message
and uh you know excss bugs. So maybe we
need to maybe we need to shift that a
little bit. Okay. So, um, if you can
solve this anxiety about the money
earning thing and get to a point where
you feel pretty confident no matter what
you do, a weekend you'll find a bug or
that that's sufficient amount, you know,
amount of money or a couple bugs, then
is that is your long-term goal to
continue in Bug Bounty forever, you
know, uh, or or are you going to try to
do something else? Um, like is that the
kind of lifestyle you want? Oh.
I guess I've never seriously thought
about like those like long-term thing. M
um I feel like as long as I mean with
obviously with the AI thing things are
changing but uh yeah for now what I'm
thinking is as long as I can keep
growing as a hacker and or not even as a
hacker keep growing as a human being and
keep learning stuff just as hacking but
maybe some other things too you know
that's keep growing those muscles like
you've been doing in the gym. And that's
that's also you know of course that's a
part of it and if I can feel that I I'm
generally happy then maybe like in long
run I might think do feel different
things in 10 years 12 years but that's
not my you know
things to consider right now something
that you're thinking too much about okay
so all right so summarizing to this
point your goal is to continue growth
continue growing as a hacker continue
growing as a person and we don't have
any like super mega long-term goals for
the time being. And the way you're
approaching that growth currently is by
coming here trying to learn via osmosis
of us collaborating on bugs or me
showing you what I'm finding um and
trying to attack new vulnerability types
yourself if you can.
And this um this main problem with
full-time Book Bounty and your lifestyle
as it currently is is this anxiety
piece. But you think that will go away
if you can continue to grow and gain
more confidence as a hacker?
Um, yeah.
So, so for one one one thing I want to
say I'm sitting here smiling at you
because I Go ahead. One thing I want to
say is not like like if if I say anxiety
that that sounds as a
little sound way bigger than the thing I
have. It's not like anxiety that I like
that I I'm I always have like every
minute or something like that. It's
something that I always think of if I
think about my career. So it's not too
like it doesn't affect your life that
much or it does not that much like it's
not like depressing sure super heavy
anxiety. So that's one thing and so that
is why if I for example find if I can
double my findings like numbers I think
I'd be I'd be pretty yeah in good shape
I guess. Okay. All right. So, you know
what I was what I'm going to tell you,
of course, is that as a hacker with more
than double your findings, you know, in
in the past
years, that worry doesn't go away from
being better at hacking, right? the
worry goes away from getting rid of the
worry, you know, like rather than get,
you know, trying to solve it from by
trying to scale up. And the way that I
mean, I wish I had more concrete advice
for you, uh, you know, besides just kind
of give it up to God and be like, I I
trust that things are going to be fine.
Um, but I know that for me it did help
to look
at to to look at other people that have
succeeded and how much risk they've
taken in their lives, you know, like
like you, Musk. Yeah. I mean, like I
mean, sure, but like, you know, any I'm
thinking more of those people that are
like, "All right, you know what? I'm
going to buy and I've got 60 bucks to my
name. I'm going to get a $50 bus ticket
to New York City." You know, like those
sort of guys, right? and then you've got
$10, you know, like and and when you
compare it to these people that kind of
really put a lot of take a lot of risk
and and still succeed and it's still
fine. Um you you look at us with like I
mean let's just be conservative two
years of uh you know salary stored up in
the
bank. What is the risk? You know and and
and I I don't know. I think it's
something that you got to kind of
practice. Yeah. Yeah, like you have to
sit down and you have to practice
intentionally being like, "No, I am
fine. I'm going to practice that. I'm
going to practice saying I am, you know,
this anxiety is not going to direct me.
This shai is not going to, you know,
exactly is not going to, you know,
affect the way that I'm dealing with
this." Um, and so I don't know. I would
definitely recommend trying to approach
that a little bit more from a mental
perspective. Yeah. than from a from a um
than than from a a logistics perspective
or a hacker growth perspective. But I
think hacker growth is a great goal and
it aligns with your goals anyway. So
maybe it'll just solve itself. Yeah,
that's the last thing I wanted to say is
you know either way that's that's my
goal. So uh I'll try to reduce like get
rid of anxiety and try to get better at
hacker. I think that's just do them both
simultaneously. Yeah. And then like
hopefully we'll come back to this fall
like two years later and like oh I'm a
I'm a hacker guru. Yeah, there you go.
That's great, right? And I mean it's
awesome also I to look back on on you
know where look at where we are at now
and look at where we were you know even
at this last episode in in 2023. You
know you've grown a ton as a hacker
since then. And if you compare it to
2021 I think which is when you started
hacking. Was it 2021 or was it 2021?
2021. Yeah. when you started hacking,
you know, it's a totally different
world. Like I honestly remember you not
even really like you pretty much just
used the computer to write essays. Yeah.
You know, and
like Jason,
who who is Jason?
That's great. Um but yeah, so that's
that's a lot of growth in a couple
years. And that that should be another
thing that gives you confidence, you
know, like in in four years, you've gone
from, you know, not knowing who who JSON
was, you know, to, uh, the position now
where you're able to make double your
your, you know, consultant salary, uh,
just doing Bugani full-time and betting
on your own skill against these very
hardened companies. So, um, you're in a
good in a good spot, man. So, I think
you should feel good about that.
Um, let me see if there's anything else
that we had on here. We could talk about
live hacky events uh and your experience
with that, but um to be honest, I think
that we should just switch over to
Reflector and talk about some of your
your technical work. Um, and I don't
know. I I I might put a little segment
in before the mentorship side and flip
the order of these. I don't know. So, we
we'll see. But um reflector I guess is a
project you've been working on recently
that is was a Kaido plugin uh and you've
made improvements to it and I kind of
just wanted to take a second to kind of
go through reflector uh the changes
you've made and why you've made those
changes and the results that you're
seeing from it already. So can you tell
us a little bit about the improvements
you made? Yeah, so reflector is a I
forgot whose u plugin was it but
something Bix I think. Bix plugin. Yeah.
To check reflected XSS. Yeah. So they
take like C parameter and and body
parameter when it's a X I forgot the Xw
for neural encoded. Yeah, I got it.
Yeah, I haven't I haven't yet. Uh
anyways, so that so they they take those
values and see if it's reflected on
response and if those parameters are
values are reflected, they send like
single quote double quotes bracket to
see if those reflect too. Okay. And so
searching for basic reflected XSS double
quote single quote angle bracket. Yeah.
And that's that's what they do. And I
I've been using it for like three four
months. Mhm. These are I I think I found
a couple bugs and it's it's a really
good plugin. So, I like it. But the
thing is they have a lot of false
positives too. So, as
like Oh, no. They they don't have a lot
of false positives. They have a lot of
false negatives. So, false negatives.
Okay. Yeah. So, that's why uh last week
or two weeks ago, I like just thought
maybe I improve it a little bit to to
work to make it work better. and then
ended up like spending like a week. I
love I love you know we we sat down and
we were like sort of brainstormed a
little bit on what approach we wanted to
use to improve reflector and uh and you
know we we we wrote out the whole
algorithm and everything and then you're
like okay yeah I should probably have
this done by later today or like
tomorrow at the latest and I was like
yeah right you know I say that every day
for five days exactly exactly and it's
like oh okay you know we got just one
more day just one just a couple bugs to
fix so yeah major major credit to
anybody who develops a Kaido plugin or
or Burp plugin. I mean it takes a lot of
work uh and it takes a lot of edge case
tweaking you know to get something
working the way you want it to work. So
what what improvements did you make and
uh what result did that have? So there
just like four or five improvements. The
first one is just uh send uh uh analyze
cookie too. No like send like check
cookie values to and if that reflects
then I'll test father and that's one.
The other one, another thing I improved
upon is they always send the same
payload for any reflection. So they
check reflection. There's any if there's
any reflection, they send like test
payload underscore
uh single code double quote closing
bracket and they send that and then they
check if that reflects. But the problem
is sometimes you know if that exact
string reflects. Yeah. If that exact
string reflects.
Maybe some server might not respond if
they're bracket but you know like may
like for example within uh JavaScript
like script tag context you might want
script tag quote context you might want
either quote to break out of the string
or uh bracket to to the script tag.
Yeah. And maybe server only
sanitizes string uh the quote right and
in that case if you send like a payload
single code double quote um bracket even
when server allows bracket to be
reflected because single code doesn't
reflect reflector doesn't say it's
vulnerable. Ah okay. So yeah. So like
maybe or or maybe you often see this
with entities too like uh maybe like a a
double quote and a single quote you know
get encoded uh get entity encoded or
something like that or URL encoded but
then the angle bracket doesn't because
those single and double quote got entity
encoded or whatever. Now the string
match fails. Yeah. And uh it's not an it
doesn't find that it was reflected. Yes.
Yes. Ah okay. Also probably uh another
issue they had was they check single
code double quote it's not really issue
but they they only check single code
double quote bracket. So for example if
you have injection point in HTML
attribute
and without like non-qued HTML attribute
non-coded HTML attribute. Okay. Yeah.
You want either slash or space to break
out of the content. Yes. Not really
break out. Yeah. So, so that's what I
wanted to do is you know parse the DOM
or you know just check the DOM before
sending payload to see where it reflects
like if it's in script like quoted
script script tag if it's in HTML if
it's in HTML attribute or if it's in a
string within script tag and such and I
what I do is I check that and based off
of that generate payload that includes
one of special characters like just one
of the special characters just one of
the script characters. Okay. So if you
need like two different characters like
within like a string of script tag you
need a quote and script uh bracket. So I
generate two payloads and send them
individually
to check the
um the the reflection. Sure. Yeah. That
so that's like a major thing I modified.
So you with that you still end up you
end up having to send a lot more
requests though, right? And if you're
just doing one of them at a time and I
also have to um uh parse response text
into DOM and that that gives a little
bit more like a how how did you solve
that? What I mean are you is it is it
causing a lot of overhead? Is it I mean
so I I'm trying like I'm trying to find
a good balance here and what I'm doing
right now is one I uh put the rate
limiter so I only send like one request
per like 0.5 second or 1 second. Oh
really? Okay interesting within the
plugin and the other thing is I try not
I try to reduce the time I the plugin
parses the response text. So obviously
you need one parse before sending
payload because you need context
analysis.
Okay. So the the normal request passes
through the proxy. Yeah. You see
reflection check. You you check the
value and you check the response to see
if it's reflected. It if it uh if it is
reflected you then parse the DOM. Yeah.
I I parse the DOM. Actually there's
another step before that. I don't I
don't know if it's a good thing to dive
into this. Yeah. No, let's go.
deep podcast. Yeah. Yeah. So before that
I check the value of each um parameter
value because for example if value is
true or false or you know undefined
there could be a lot of you know in
response there could be a lot of true
and false and undefined. Sure. So if you
just check reflection on string based
comparison you get a lot of false
negatives false positives. False
positives. Yeah. And since I do uh I do
a dumper psing within uh serial un
serialized HTML. If there are too many
true or like if the value is just a like
one length and if I try to or one or
something like that be so much overhead
plus so so many false positives. So if I
find such like common values or two
short values then I try to send like
like 10 characters long alpha numeric
random value and resend the request for
all the parameters that have such like
either common or short values and see if
response doesn't break like for example
if you mess with session cookie and the
response for three right so I need to
check that
But but anyways, I try to find as many
uh such common values and short values
that could be replaced with random
values to to minimize the false
positives of like oh yeah it reflected
from the you know is admin parameter you
know true and now there's like 50 trs in
the body. Okay, so I do that and if ever
those changes
uh breaks the response, I give up on
those parameters for now. Maybe I I
should work on that. But for now, seems
to make sense. Yeah. Yeah. I I give up
on that. Maybe just typing on them or
something like that, right? Yeah. And
then so now I have like like normal
maybe not normal but let's say normal
parameter with a long long values or not
common values and uh some others with
you know generated values and I I take
all of those and and then un serialize
HTML and see unerize HTML and check
where where they all reflect and see if
it's in like script or such and based
off of that I reject. So you you then
you parse the DOM and you identify where
the reflection occurred and you figure
out what context it's in. Yeah. So if
it's an HTML attribute that's easy, you
know, you can just find that. Do I and
then does the DOM parsing engine that
you use tell you what kind of quote is
in the the um the attribute item
attribute? Yes. for for that no maybe
there's a better way but I don't the the
approach I took is uh I take the value
mhm using the like attribute value
properly and then I check
u values next to them then ah and then
you just grab the previous character
yeah and then if it's a single quote
double quote and that's easy okay so
then so then you know you identify okay
we're in a d we're in a double quoted
HTML attribute context we're in a single
quote HTML view context or we're just in
you know a a script or a uh an HTML tag
you know that sort of environment and
then you define a smart payload
specifically for that that um context
and for script tag you know you can't do
such things of like taking string right
as opposed to taking attribute values
you can't do that with don't person so I
just count all these like characters
from the beginning of script text note
of the script tag and then if I find
single code now single quote context I
found double quote but it's in single
quote context I don't change it I found
escape oh escape so the next character
is invalid even if it's single quote
doesn't matter so skip it single oh it's
single quote so it's out of single quote
context kind of like that wow so you
have you read through each index of the
whole script tag
jeez I feel like that would be pretty
intensive Have you have you like have
you looked at all at your at your CPU
and is it like freaking out or is it I
mean No, it's it's been okay. It's it's
been okay like there's no issue but
maybe maybe thanks to my Mac. Yeah.
Well, you do have a pretty powerful Mac.
Yeah. So, okay. So, then you know the
way you figure out so oftentimes what
happens is like they'll be like var you
know name equals single quote and then
like reflection from inside the script
tag, right? And whenever we see that
obviously we're really happy about that.
That's like a very interesting
environment. Um, but you need to know
whether we're in a double quote
environment, a single, you know, a
single quote environment. Uh, uh, do do
you do the back ticks? You do the back
ticks as well. Nice. So, like a backtick
environment, that sort of thing. And the
back ticks are interesting because I
guess I guess if you're in a backtick
environment, you could also
do like the dollar sign uh, curly
bracket things. Oh, yeah. And then you
could you could break out. So those
become sensitive characters in the in
the I'll add that. Yeah,
I just got you more dev time. Uh I've
never seen a reflection inside of a
inside of that. That's pretty weird
situation. Yeah, template template
literal environment. Um but then okay,
so you identify that you count the
number of strings, you know, double
quotes or single quotes that you see
because it should always be even. There
should never be an uneven amount unless
it's escaped. So that makes sense. I
don't count the number I encounter. I
just like I just hold like you know if I
encounter single call I'm like oh this
is single code environment and I do that
till my reflection. That's smart dude
that's that is a that's a good example
of a really like simple and beautiful
algorithm to solve a really I don't know
though like this is maybe just thanks to
my Mac like I said it could be your Mac
just being amazing but to be honest it
doesn't sound like it should be too
intensive you know like like you anytime
you search a string you go through every
index you know, so I think it's probably
I mean it should be roughly O of N,
right? I think it should happen
linearly, you know, just with just one
one iteration through. So I don't think
that's too computationally. I hope so.
Yeah. Um that's a beautiful solution. So
then you avoid having to use like a a
JavaScript grammar parsing engine. I
don't know, maybe that's a better way,
but I'm not using it for now. Yeah. No,
that's good. That's good. And then yeah,
you don't have to do any like um syntax
trees or anything like that. That's
good. So then you identify, you know,
what characters are sensitive in that
environment. You put those in the URL.
You know, are you URL encoding or not
URL encoding before you send? Yeah, I
encode them. I URL encode them. Yeah.
Because usually that's what you have to
do, right? Yeah. I wonder if there's any
merit to sending a URL encoded and URL
decoded. Maybe like cache situation is
something I was thinking like because
then you can just send like an encoded
character via pro proxy and if that
causes some cash issue but that's not
what I'm looking for right now. No,
that's not what what you're looking for.
I have seen sometimes though where it's
like if you send a unuroded double quote
it will reflect a URL unencoded double
quote. But the problem with that is
browsers don't allow that. Yeah. Yeah.
So, it's going to get URL encoded anyway
automatically. Um, I don't know if they
I don't think they allow that in the
body parameter either, I think, or in
like body parameters. I don't think so.
Yeah. Okay. So, that would that would
kind of trigger some really annoying
excesses because, you know, maybe it
does reflect a double quote, but it
actually and that happens with the
reflector. Oh, did it? Yeah. Oh my gosh.
So, sometimes I was like, yes. You know,
like it happens like and you can't it
can't actually be exploited. Wow, that's
a pain.
Okay. So, that that seems like an
awesome approach. Um,
uh, is there anything any other
improvements that you want to make to it
or any improvements that you made to
Reflector that um, you know, any other
improvements that you made that you want
to talk about or I think I think that's
about it that we have. It's not like a
too huge over project. So, yeah, I've
been surprised by the results. Like I
remember you you spent so much time
deving it that we've only had about a
day to test it before this podcast and
like you were just navigating to random
bug bounty sites and you were seeing
boop boop boop and like all of these
third parties were like popping. Yeah.
So good thing about it is they don't
have too much like they don't have false
uh positives pretty much at all. Maybe
there are a lot of false post negatives.
I got to look into it. But because of
that, like when something pops up on
findings, I I I can be like, "Oh, I'll
check it." I think it would be very hard
to have a false negative, you know? I I
think the way that the you've
implemented the strategy is like pretty
solid because I know you're using like a
canary on either side, right? You're
like sandwiching the payload in a canary
as well. Um, so you have high integrity
on whether it's actually reflected or
not. Um, so I think that's I think I
think you just came up with a pretty
solid algorithm, you know, to to check
for reflections. Um, and then I think
one of the things that we saw just
yesterday when we were working on it,
you know, you popped two third party XSS
yesterday with this and those XSS were
in iframes, right? Which is beautiful
because uh you can then use that to as a
trusted position against the main app. I
I end up finding more or issue than you
know. Yeah, that's true. That's true. It
does continue to be oath issues. Uh
yeah, you know, but or you know, maybe
you can pivot it to XSS on the main
domain via like a a trusted post message
relationship or that's also client side
accesses though, you know. Yeah. I mean,
so I mean, all right, so let's I mean
that's fine. That's fine. Yeah. So I
mean is that what you want to I mean do
you want to move away from client side
stuff then? I mean do is that is that
the TLDDR of the situation? No, I just
see what because if not you should have
flown to if so you should have flown to
go see someone else because I love
client side stuff man and not to say
that I don't find server side stuff I do
but um but I think there's something so
beautiful about client side stuff and
the chong
so all right man I think that's all we
had on reflector
um oh man I guess the time has come for
me to do the Japanese version of the
podcast huh all right well
Critical thinking.
[Music]
Let's Let's do it.
That's
collaboration.
competition.
Excs htm.
[Music]
No resources. No resources.
Inner
[Music]
HTML. Relative
resources.
Enter
HTML base
tag
h inject.
relative path.
Inject HF
[Music]
attribute double double
quote. Yeah.
It was encoded.
HF
attribute relative
[Music]
path absolute path
Injection location.path Path
name
index index index.
So base HF knee.
You know what?
uh location path
Normaliz HTML entities.
Hex
two demo.
Fragment HTML entity.
Fore
HTML
HTML.
Mhm. JavaScript
[Music]
Excess.
forchech.
Bug bountych.
[Music]
integity. Yeah, he's
Facebook.
[Music]
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, Mhm.
You know,
[Applause]
No recital.
[Music]
So,
Japanese.
Unicorn.
[Music]
Auto commission.
document.
So
I goch foreign.
[Music]
and GTF.
Oh mych.
So you don't
[Music]
Yeah. Yeah.
outside the outer side the outside of
the bug bounty
industry today's
Doing gotch.
Fore. So you send me
automation. CTF
No.
Sorry.
Uh, so he says
Mhm.
design. Stuck it there.
So
[Music]
Dopamine.
Okay.
podcast.
I'm
So,
so not old
[Music]
Okay. Bug bounty.
TJP. Peoplechech.
[Music]
Yeah. Okay.
Johnny. And that's a wrap on this
episode of Critical Thinking. Thanks so
much for watching to the end, y'all. If
you want more critical thinking content,
uh, or if you want to support the show,
head over to
ctbb.show/isord. You can hop in the
community. There's lots of great
highlevel hacking discussion happening
there on top of master classes,
hackalongs, exclusive content, and a
full-time hunters guild if you're a
full-time hunter. It's a great time,
trust me. All right, I'll see you there.